Hey there, friends!
This is a super beginner, hand holding tutorial for Codex.
We'll begin with installation.
I'll guide you step by step through Codex's basic
to advanced features,
and its latest mobile operations,
using ten practical scenarios to master it.
From now on, for any Agent products that come out,
you'll be able to grasp them by analogy
and handle them with ease.
I've compiled this episode's notes
into a document—see you in the comments!
So the value of this episode
is just *BAM! BAM! BAM!asterisk through the roof!
A like, save, and follow are the bare minimum. Tuition paid?
Let's get started!
Before we start, I'll explain the difference between Codex and Claude Code. Essentially, both Anthropic's and OpenAI's versions have evolved from programming to general purpose agents.
Claude Code from these developers
defaults to the Claude model,
but can be swapped for any other. Codex
desktop only supports OpenAI's GPT models.
Now, Codex desktop is more user friendly,
better suited for zero tech white collar workers.
Claude Code, however, provides more freedom.
Functionally, Claude Code was originally the most complete,
pioneering features
like Skills, MCPs, commands, Hooks, and remote control.
But lately, CC's updates are slower than Codex's,
and it's more for professional developers.
Codex, meanwhile, offers powerful browser and computer control,
and features the latest Image two image generation model.
And yesterday, they released the mobile app and hooks,
allowing you to use your phone's ChatGPT to control
Codex on your computer.
Pricing and quotas? Codex's allowances are generous;
a twenty dollars membership is ample,
and they won't ban your account.
For Claude Code, official accounts are often unavailable,
meaning you'll typically pay for API usage
directly—it's a pay as you go system.
For writing, I like using Claude Code
with the Claude model,
as Opus four point six's
writing and planning abilities are incredibly strong.
Codex also excels at execution and problem solving.
For daily office tasks,
I prefer Codex, and for coding, I use both.
So, the takeaway is: for beginners,
Codex is awesome,
but if you can manage, using both is the perfect setup.
But their logic is the same;
master one, and the other comes easily.
I've also made a full Claude Code tutorial.
If you want to leverage both,
check it out. OK, let's officially start using Codex.
The only thing you need is a ChatGPT account;
a free one is fine, though with a smaller limit.
Once you have an account, just go to their official website,
install it, and log in with your ChatGPT account.
Then, for these settings,
we can just pick something random for now,
like 'Daily Work'—we can always change it later anyway.
And there we go!
Once you're in, you'll see this chat window,
which looks a lot like ChatGPT.
Let's open up both sidebars—they look quite familiar.
On the left, conversations and tasks;
the middle is for chat,
and the right probably displays results—most can guess.
So, let's skip the interface for now and just start using it.
That's my secret recipe for exploring any AI tool.
When I open a new interface,
I first ignore everything else.
I just find the chat box and start chatting.
I'll find a button
I understand and press it.
You'll learn by doing.
See? I've shared my secret recipe with you all,
so now you're my disciples!
Alright, no formalities. Let's focus on studies.
So, the first Codex capability to understand
is local file operations,
its defining capability,
setting it apart from conversational AI's.
Because in the past, when we used ChatGPT,
if we wanted it to see our local content,
we only had two options.
One way is to copy and paste it into the chat,
and the other is to upload the files
within the formats and quantities it allows.
But Codex is different.
It can independently read and manipulate our local files,
with no limits on quantity.
For example, as an editor,
I have over eighty video clips stored locally
that I need for my edits.
But the filenames are all a mess— totally incomprehensible.
So, I want to rename them based on their content,
so that when we look at the filenames,
we'll know what each clip is about.
Now, ChatGPT definitely can't do this,
but Codex can. Notice these two places;
both display a concept: 'Project'.
So let's select that,
and once we choose 'Project,'
it prompts us to pick a local folder.
So, once we select this folder, it becomes our project.
Codex can freely read and manipulate all the files inside.
Of course, this requires us to grant it permissions.
Look at the permission options here.
We're currently on default,
but clicking it reveals three modes.
So, the default permissions mean that
within our current folder,
it can freely read and write these files.
But if it wants to connect to the internet,
download something for us,
or touch any files outside of this folder,
it can't do that.
Should it need to,
it will ask for elevated permissions,
requiring our agreement to proceed.
Auto Review, as the name implies,
means an AI automatically reviews actions,
deciding if they're dangerous.
If it's risky, it'll ask us; otherwise,
for safe tasks like official software downloads,
it'll just do it.
Auto review is more flexible and smarter than default,
so just choose this one.
And finally, there's Full Access.
This means Codex can do pretty much anything
on your computer—it can modify or delete any file,
and run commands anywhere.
For example, it might delete your Claude Code.
Kidding aside, it usually won't act up.
AI has no jealousy.
Oh.
So for everyone, especially beginners,
just pick auto review and trust the AI.
Can we really review better than it, right?
OK, so we've selected that video folder from earlier,
and let's go on and make our unreasonable demands.
Have it rename all the video files in this folder
based on what's actually in the footage.
It's starting.
And look, it's being super smart—first, it checked
how many videos we actually have.
Then, it chose to extract key frames
to figure out what the content was.
Plus, it even knew not to look at each image one by one;
instead, it stitched them together into thumbnails
and viewed them group by group.
OK, and just like that,
all the filenames in this folder have been changed.
And Codex didn't ask for elevated permissions,
as all operations stayed within this folder.
So, let's check if everything lines up correctly,
shall we?
Okay, pianist concert hall, right.
Snowy mountain combat, right.
Cheongsam woman in Night Alley selling hot drinks.
Wow, and the naming even follows a clear format: number,
character, scene, action.
The level of detail AI puts in ... man,
you just gotta give it credit.
Also, we can actually start multiple different conversations
within the same project.
Their contexts are all different,
but they can all access our files
and this project at any time.
For example, in another conversation,
we can give it a different task:
have it figure out how to edit all the landscape videos
into one single clip.
Wow, it can actually edit!
It figured out some tools on its own,
asked us for some permissions,
and then used FFmpeg to stitch them all together.
It's all the landscape shots, edited into one clip.
Okay, so if we want to create a new project,
we can manually create it right here,
and it will also automatically create a folder
on our local machine.
And throughout our conversation with Codex,
any files the Agent generates—PDF's, Markdown,
PPTs—will be saved directly onto our local computer.
Okay, so by now you should get it.
Codex can access our local files at any time to read content,
write files,
delete files, and move files around.
The folder's contents become the context
Codex can access anytime.
So, each 'project' here corresponds to a local folder.
So, how much context would a task like that just now cost us?
We can see it right here.
So, this circle indicates
how much GPT five point five context
this conversation and its operations have used.
Hovering over it shows more details.
As context fills up, Codex automatically compresses it for us.
But actually, once a task is wrapped up,
you don't have to wait for it to get almost full
for it to auto compress.
We can also manually compress the context ourselves
by using the '/compress' command.
This helps the model focus better on our new task
and also saves a bit of our context quota.
Of course, aside from this conversation context allowance,
you're probably also wondering—whether you're a free user
or a Plus member—
how much total quota I have left to use, right?
There are two ways to check this.
First, on the left side,
under Settings, click 'Remaining Quota'
to see what's left for the next five hours and for the week.
It even prompts when the quota resets,
making its design far more user friendly than Claude's.
Or, another way
is to just type a forward slash in the chat box
and find this 'status' option.
So, once you open this status view,
your session will continuously display
your context allowance—those five hour and one week limits.
Honestly, Codex's allowance is quite generous;
its twenty dollars credit
should easily cover most white collar users' frequent needs.
OK, and while we're at it,
let's also talk about the model selection here.
So, once you click on that,
we can select the speed. 'Fast' is like an express lane,
which will use up more of our quota.
You can pick other models here,
but pretty much everyone goes with GPT five point five
because it's just better.
Then, select the intelligence level.
Actually, Medium's usually enough,
so we'll go High.
OK, so this little microphone icon
is obviously for voice input,
which is way faster than typing.
However, its transcription isn't as fast
as a dedicated voice app.
Still, I'd highly recommend using voice input.
Alright, so through that local file processing example,
we've now gotten a look at some of Codex's common features.
Codex's second capability is command line tools.
Regarding permissions, we noted that by default,
it can read and write files,
but not execute commands or network operations.
So, what do these commands mean?
The previous example used it to extract video frames
and stitch multiple videos together.
The FFmpeg it used is a command line tool.
And there are some familiar commands,
like when we clone a GitHub repository in the terminal.
Or, as you're likely familiar with, entering commands
in the command line
to download Node and its dependencies.
So, Codex's second major capability
is that, with our permission,
it can use our terminal to do these things for us.
So, let's have Codex help us install some stuff
that's usually super complicated for beginners.
First, common dependencies like Node.js, Git, etc.
They're essential tools for various Agents or projects.
So, previously, you'd manually install these dependencies
by following tutorials and copying commands.
Now, we just tell Codex, 'Help me install Node.'
send the JS over to it.
And that's because these things are all pretty common stuff.
So, in our auto audit permission mode,
it didn't need elevated permissions,
just installed it for us expertly.
Then, the second category includes
popular new Agents with a steep learning curve, like Hermes.
You can even get Codex to install its own competitor,
Claude Code,
and it'll even teach us how to use it!
So let's install Hermes.
I don't even need its website or repo
address—I'll just tell it to install Hermes,
mentioning it's trending.
Hey, it'll go search on its own
and figure out which one it is for us.
Then, following the official docs,
it went ahead and installed everything for us,
and even verified that it was all set up.
See? Let's try starting it up
as it said. Hey, it really did get installed for us!
So we won't go through the rest of the configuration here,
but you guys should get the idea.
With Codex, those complex five hundred and ninety nine
buck deployments?
You can just have Codex
do them, saving you five hundred and ninety nine!
Plus, if we run into any issues while using it,
we can even take a screenshot and ask Codex about it.
From minor issues to upgrade problems,
Codex can fix them directly.
Super convenient, right?
The third category, less crucial,
can also manage software apps like Cursor or Antigravity.
Things we'd normally download manually online,
it can also download and uninstall.
When using Codex,
I'd actually recommend downloading an Agent IDE,
because right now, Codex has a drawback:
it can't open our files for us to edit manually.
So, while this sidebar
lets you see some of the file structure
and content,
you can't actually edit any of it.
So, you can have Codex
download one of your choice—say, we'll
just download it like this.
So once that's downloaded,
we'll run a 'git init' to initialize it.
Then, this thing will pop up in the top right corner,
letting us open our project in an editor
anytime for manual editing.
The fourth category is important:
the agent's frequently used Skills, MCPs, and CLIs.
Codex also supports Skills and MCPs,
which we'll discuss later.
For now, I'll pick two
for you to install for our combined examples.
Now, these Skills and CLIs, generally speaking,
aren't as well known as major projects like Git.
So, it's best to find its specific repository
or its official website address.
For instance, we download 'Find Skill' – a tool to find skills.
We just copy its link to Codex
and tell it, 'Install this skill.'
While that's installing,
another major Codex benefit is parallel task processing.
So while it's doing that,
we can totally start another chat
and have it download something else.
So, let's download the Feishu CLI.
Feishu CLI is a classic example.
That's because some software is getting 'AI fied,'
turning almost every in app action into a command
so that Agents can easily operate them.
Let's send this link over and have it start downloading.
So over here, it'll show the status
of each task being processed—this spinning icon
means it's currently running.
So, this blue dot means it's finished.
Sometimes, you might also see an icon
that indicates you need to request permissions.
OK, so here, the 'Find Skill' feature is already installed.
For Feishu CLI, it'll guide us through authorization.
Just follow its prompts.
Okay, once Feishu CLI is installed,
Codex can help us with various tasks
in Feishu—like writing documents,
sending messages, or creating calendar events.
I use it almost every day.
Alright, all done!
In this small section,
we used natural language for Codex to install Hermes Node,
Feishu CLI,
and a lot more for us.
This is Codex's second most common capability
as an Agent: using the command line.
And with this capability and demo,
I hope you get one key takeaway.
Basically, many of the things we want to do on our computers
these days
can be handled by a desktop Agent like Codex.
Codex's third capability: persistent memory.
As mentioned in my Claude Code video,
CC has a manual persistent memory, CLAUDE.md.
and an automatic memory system,
both of which store things
we want the Agent to remember long term,
like rules, preferences, and our personal information.
which exist as local files on our computer.
and then, at the right moment,
inject these memories into the Agent as context.
Codex, similarly, has these two persistent memory systems.
In Codex, manual persistent memory is AGENTS.md,
plus an automatic memory.
Let's open Settings, find Personalization.
So, these custom instructions you see here
actually take effect globally throughout the system.
AGENTS.md is immediately sent as context to the large model
when you chat with Codex on any project.
So, you can manually write it in here yourself.
But personally, I prefer to just tell
Codex directly in our chat.
For example, I'd say: 'From now on,
for Feishu doc changes,
use your own dedicated text
color and strikethrough for edits.'
Don't directly modify.
And save this for me in the global AGENTS.md.
Okay, it's written. Opening 'Personalization', we see this new set of rules has indeed been added.
So in practice, it will then follow this rule of ours.
For example, I've got a Feishu doc here
with my requested changes commented on the side.
I can send this link to Codex.
I'll have it make some edits based on my comment on the side.
And since the Feishu CLI is set up with proper permissions,
Codex can now directly manipulate our documents.
OK, let's see how it turned out.
Sure enough, it used purple text and strikethrough
to make the document edits for us.
This is the global AGENTS.md,
ideal for general principles applicable to all tasks.
For example, our work habits, like speaking Chinese,
our preferences, and leaving revision marks in documents.
Then there's project level AGENTS.md,
whose long term memory is effective only in this project.
We can select a project conversation,
then open the editor
and manually create an agency.md file right there.
an `.md` file,
and then we can write some rules specific to this project.
Or, of course, you can have Codex write it for you.
My personal recommendation is,
once you have some content in your project files,
let Codex use its understanding of your project
to write it for you.
So, what about Auto Memory?
Well, as we just saw under 'Personalization,'
we need to manually turn on this Auto Memory feature.
So, its mechanism is that once enabled, Codex will,
after a conversation or task ends,
or after a brief period of inactivity,
It summarizes the conversation as a memory
and stores it somewhere.
But there are some rules:
It won't remember short conversations,
and summarizing them also consumes our quota.
So, when our quota gets too low, it won't remember.
OpenAI officially advises against manually editing
this auto memory file;
only delete unneeded information.
So, this file looks something like this.
It logs tasks individually,
primarily noting the memory's source
conversation and working directory.
And later on, when certain keywords are triggered,
it will recall this memory.
Then, further down,
are the user's preferences regarding this matter.
Then, the fifth section contains reusable knowledge
and lessons from pitfalls.
All this content is recorded by Codex itself
and will be automatically recalled for future use.
Let's not modify it for now; this format is hard to change.
More often, for clear rules and requirements,
we achieve this by organizing AGENTS.md.
After these videos, I'd like to do another one
on organizing multi level AGENTS.md.
to create a video about a super assistant
that truly understands you and handles diverse tasks.
The fourth major capability is that
Codex can directly use Image two to generate images.
However, image generation is just a minor feature.
So, in this chapter, we're not just using image generation;
we'll build a complete personal homepage.
and get a feel for some of Codex's uses and functions
for beginner developers.
Let's create a 'Personal Homepage' project.
Then, let's click on this plus sign and turn on Plan Mode,
since building a website is a bit more complex.
So, by turning on Plan Mode,
it will first lay out a detailed plan for us,
then acts upon our confirmation.
Plan Mode is great for tasks that are somewhat complex,
or when you haven't quite figured things out yourself
and want to work out a plan with the AI.
So let's say we're in that second scenario—
we haven't really thought it through—
and we just tell it, "I want to make a personal homepage."
So, you can see that since it found no content in our project,
it's using this selection box to ask for more details.
You can pick any of these options based on your own needs,
so I'll go with 'Personal Brand'.
And if these options aren't quite right,
you can pick the last one to add your specific requirements.
For example, I want a narrative, premium feel,
select 'for partners,'
no personal photos,
bilingual Chinese and English, etc.
It really asked us many questions.
Finally, it gave us a detailed plan
and asked if we’d implement it.
So, the basic plan looks fine to us,
but we can also add some adjustments.
For example, we just mentioned using its Image
two generation capability,
but that's not reflected here.
Let's add: 'Use Image two
to generate more high end images for the webpage,'
then we'll submit.
So it's asking what kind of 'high end' feel we want?
And if we click the exclamation mark,
we can see what that style means.
I love the little details of this product.
Let's go with its recommendation.
The new plan looks fine to me—go ahead.
OK, it's initializing the project,
gradually generating it for us.
So, this process will definitely take some time.
In the meantime, let me share a little bit more knowledge
with you all. Ooh!
Wow, its first image! Artistic, truly the best Image
two. Now, the point I want to add is 'guidance'.
So, if you're running a long task in Codex
and feel like it's starting to go off track,
you can always step in to correct its course.
For example, let's add that
the image should have a stronger human touch
and not such a cold color tone.
I'm an AI blogger.
Let's send that out.
You'll see it didn't interrupt our task
or send immediately; it's actually queued up here.
So, on the right, this guidance button says
it won't interrupt the model's run;
it'll send it after the next tool call.
That's a really great feature!
Let's click on it, and it'll send it out.
This feature prevents Codex from going full speed
down the wrong path,
blowing through our quota,
or having to rerun a whole task from scratch.
Now, for another neat little feature,
let's find a task that's already finished
and check out the AI's response.
Beneath every AI reply, there's this button called 'Fork'.
This means we can start a new conversation from here anytime,
ideal when the conversation is good
and the context is valuable.
But as we chat further
and things start to go a bit off track ...
oh, and there's also a little pet feature!
In 'Settings' >'Appearance,' you'll find a selection of pets.
You can even click 'Create' and have Codex
generate a custom pet
based on what it knows about you.
So let's click 'Awaken Pet'.
This little desktop pet will be on your desktop,
with a bubble showing Codex's current activity.
Beyond that, it doesn't seem to do much.
OK, finally, after seventy five minutes of running,
the webpage is done.
Let's check out the results.
Because Codex has a built in preview browser,
we can just open the right sidebar and make it bigger.
Hmm, this webpage looks great.
While most Agents do this,
this preview browser has another benefit.
If we click the annotation button in the top right,
we can select elements on this page for revision notes.
and regenerating images.
For example, let's say we want this logo to be a bit bigger,
then annotate this image here to add a person,
and okay, delete this one.
So then, these comments will be added to the dialogue box,
and once we hit send, it'll make the changes
based on our feedback.
Pretty convenient, right?
Now that our project has a preliminary form,
let's revisit AGENTS.md.
Now's a great time for Codex to generate a project level
AGENTS.md for us,
with some content already in place.
Let's open up the editor and take a look ...
Nice! The project's background,
all the info, rules, and file paths have been written out.
So from now on, whether we start a new chat
or our chat history has been cleared,
Codex can instantly understand our project basics
via its project AGENTS.md.
OK, let's leave it like this
for now—no fine tuning—and get ready to deploy it live.
Of course, you can always refine it yourself,
and simply replace the webpage info with your real details.
So, to deploy this,
we need to talk about Codex's fifth core capability: Plugins.
In the current version of Codex,
plugins mostly serve to connect our Agent
with external platforms,
tools, and services.
It's essentially a complete collection of
what we call Skills,
MCP CLI, and similar tools—like handling emails,
calendars, or GitHub.
So, let's click the Plugins bar on the left;
you'll see several built in plugins are already enabled
by default.
For example, there's Browser Control,
Mac specific Screen Control,
GitHub, spreadsheets, PowerPoint, and so on.
Now, its plugin page isn't translated into Chinese,
so I've listed their Chinese meanings and functions for you.
You can install them as needed—just click the plus sign.
So, let's head over to the 'Coding' section first,
as plugins make deployment super convenient.
Both Vercel and Netlify are fine.
Vercel suits those with a domain;
otherwise, accessing it from China might be an issue.
If you don't have a domain,
Netlify is better for China access.
Let's click plus to install.
And if you haven't selected GitHub,
make sure to pick that one too.
Then, let's go back to the chat and tell it
we want to use Netlify to deploy this website for us.
We don't even have to worry about
how it deploys things—whatever it needs to do, it'll tell us.
OK, so it noticed we weren't logged in
and automatically popped up this login link.
So, I'd recommend logging in with your GitHub account—it's
the most convenient way.
So once you're logged in,
it'll know you're authenticated
and continue with the deployment for us—
and just like that, it's done!
This link is our final website—just send this out,
and others will be able to visit your personal homepage.
Now, if you want to swap this domain
for one you bought yourself,
you know who to ask—Codex.
Just ask Codex, and it'll teach you.
Is AI good or what?
Just a couple clicks deliver results
most couldn't achieve with money.
Okay, I'll curb my old timer's amazement.
Now, let's circle back to the plugins we just installed.
Actually, there are two other very important
built in plugins here:
Browser Use and Computer Use, plus the Chrome browser itself.
So, what are these for? Browser Use,
as the name suggests,
allows Codex to directly control your browser:
clicking pages,
taking screenshots,
filling forms.
It's typically for automating front end tests.
Of course, we can also have Codex do something fun,
like open this MBTI for a test.
Hehe, this way, you guys can get a pretty intuitive
look at how it works, right?
The mouse is moving on its own,
reading and filling in the answers,
and once this page is done, it'll automatically flip.
And after a flurry of activity, the results are in.
So GPT five point five is an INTJ!
No wonder we get along so well!
Okay, so this Chrome extension also controls a browser,
but it controls our own,
already logged in browser—it doesn't open a new one.
So, if we check that box,
it'll guide us to install a plugin in Chrome.
Once that's installed, it can then operate our own browser.
It's great that it can handle multi page browser operations
in the background,
without monopolizing our browser.
We don't have to actually wait and watch its actions;
we can just use our browser for other things while it works.
OK, 'Computer Use' is even more powerful,
controlling not just your browser but also computer apps.
However, this feature is currently only on Mac.
For example, in a new chat,
see the plugin option at the bottom of the plus menu.
Let's manually select the computer plugin.
Then, some more quirky, less useful tricks.
Play the hottest song from 'ninety nine for me,
and then send a message from my WeChat to QQ.
WeChat says: 'Please accept my like, favorite, and follow—get it?'
OK, it's thinking ... and then it sees our apps are running
and asks for permission to use this music software.
Let's hit 'Agree'.
See? Codex did that all by itself!
It's searching for songs. OK,
music's playing,
but it's still asking for WeChat permissions.
Let's grant that too.
OK, look at its little mouse cursor—it's hesitating to search
and click.
Friends, it failed. It worked last time,
but I guess WeChat is now strictly preventing
these Agent operations,
directly kicking me out.
But, it did successfully operate this music software.
In fact, I also had it use CapCut
to add music to our latest project.
So anyway, you get the idea now— it can control the browser
and it can control our computer.
But honestly, its efficiency's a bit low right now,
so I don't really use these two powerful features.
But this next thing I'm gonna talk about, Skills—now
THAT'S something
I use every single day.
Now, Skills—I've covered this often.
So if you're keen, definitely catch up.
So, a Skill is essentially our refined
set of reusable methods,
workflows, and tools.
They're basically action guides
for the Agent to perform specific tasks.
Now, because we've already had Codex install a meta Skill
for us
called 'Find Skill'...
So, when installing or finding community Skills,
you can just use Codex
to download them with natural language.
For example, let's download
an essential Anthropic front end design Skill
and the 'AI feel' remover.
So, let's send both of these to it.
They'll come in handy. It's quickly installed them for us.
So, from now on,
if you want to download a Skill
and the 'Find Skill' feature can't find it,
you can just send the link directly to Codex
and have it download it for you.
But as I said in that CC episode,
the best Skills are those you create yourself,
tailored for your own work.
There are two ways to create a Skill.
First, you can just tell Codex
what kind of Skill you want to create
and work it out through discussion with it
to get a final Skill.
The other way, which we're about to demonstrate,
is to first get the workflow running,
and then have it turned into a Skill.
This is also the recommended approach.
Let's create a skill to automate writing articles
and pairing them with images—you've probably seen this, right?
So, we'll first need to guide Codex step by step
to have it actually produce an article
that we're happy with.
Alright, let's start a new chat.
Since we just installed the GitHub plugin,
let's ask it about
the latest popular and trending GitHub projects.
OK, it did find some for us.
Now let's have it clearly explain
what each of these projects does.
Now, let's have it pick the ones with the most stars
and write us an article titled '
'This Week's Trending GitHub Projects'.
Alright, once it's written this,
it's a bit robotic.
I'd prefer it more conversational, and just five hand picked.
So let's tell it to cover these specific aspects.
So, right here, we can use that 'de AI' Skill
we just downloaded.
Let's bring it up with a slash command.
Alright, so the final result is slightly better.
But we also want to add our own fixed opening and closing,
and have it use Image two
to generate some supporting images for us.
Lastly, I also want it to not be in this format,
but rather as a Feishu document, with both text and posts.
OK, here come the results.
It did generate something,
but I feel like the images aren't rich enough.
So, after more tweaks, I was finally satisfied.
And I even added one last step: to have it
send this Feishu doc to a specific group chat
for everyone to check out.
So, here's the final result: and sure enough, it got sent out.
Actually, for those of you who want to take it even further,
you can also combine this with the browser control
we just talked about.
have it open that publish page
and post it for you right away.
So anyway, once we're happy with these results,
we can have it turn this entire process into a Skill.
So, if we type in a slash and scroll down,
we'll see that Skill right there.
We can manually call this Skill,
or say 'generate a post recommending Trending projects.'
Codex will also automatically invoke it with such phrases.
But since the real time Trending projects on GitHub
haven't been updated,
So if we call it again,
it'll most likely generate a similar article,
so we'll skip trying that.
But I think you all get the idea
now—Skills let us lock in a whole set of verified,
well tuned workflows and methods.
Next time, Codex can consistently output based on this.
The next capability is MCP.
MCP isn't widely used now,
so I'll just give a quick demo.
You'll find Codex's MCP under 'MCP Servers' in Settings.
But for beginners looking at this,
you'll probably have no idea what to fill in.
So, as we mentioned earlier,
the easiest way is to just copy the MCP link you want
and let Codex install it.
For example, let's give it a NotebookLM MCP.
It'll guide us through authorization and login,
and then we're all set.
Let's try another.
I have a notebook full of interview videos;
let's ask it.
So just like that,
Codex can now directly access these external knowledge bases
on our NotebookLM.
OK, the last Codex capability is timed tasks.
Actually, scheduled tasks themselves
aren't anything special—things
like reminding me to take my meds
or drink water every morning,
regular software can do that too.
But we're saving it for last
because it can combine all the skills we've learned before
into a whole suite of tasks.
The agent's automated, intelligent, and customized execution –
that's the real beauty of it.
For example, for the Trending project posts
Skill we just made,
we can set it to generate every three days or weekly,
on a fixed schedule.
Publish GitHub Trending project recommendations.
Isn't that an automated social media manager?
To create automated tasks,
there are two ways.
The first way is to select the Automation panel
over here. It provides some official sample templates,
though most of them are development related.
So, let's create a new automation.
Filling it out
is quite straightforward—you simply use prompts to describe
what it should do.
Then, we can choose when it should trigger here,
and we can also customize the trigger time ourselves.
Then, you can select the execution model
and thinking strength here,
and finally, just click 'create'.
But still, I'd recommend the second, simpler method:
just telling Codex directly in the chat.
So let's just tell it, "Help me create an automated task."
Every Monday at nine AM,
automatically run the 'Trending Project Recommendations' Skill,
generate a post, and send it to the group chat.
OK, so if we check back under 'Automation,'
it's already set up this task for us,
and we can change its time anytime.
Or, let's say your email, plugins,
GitHub, and Feishu are all connected to Codex.
Then you can have it summarize your completed calendar
meetings daily at six PM.
using my GitHub commits and email replies
to generate a comprehensive daily work report.
Lastly, for phone control, it's simple: just update your phone's ChatGPT and PC's Codex to their latest versions. Then ...
Just open ChatGPT on your phone,
tap Codex in the sidebar,
and it'll prompt you
to let this phone control your computer—done just like that.
And if you have multiple computers,
you can connect those up as well.
So that means whether you're out on the street,
on the subway, or at a get together with friends,
you can assign a task anytime, anywhere from your phone
and have Codex get a job done on your computer,
making it feel more like a colleague
you can work with remotely.
This feature is currently available on the free plan,
but it mainly connects to Codex on Mac systems.
Okay, so that wraps up all of Codex's core capabilities.
Let's recap.
Codex can manipulate our local files.
it can use the terminal command line tools on our computer,
it has two ways to build persistent memory,
and it can also generate images.
Plus, it can handle entire project development
through its Plan mode.
Plus, it has rich plugins
to control your browser and computer,
and can turn knowledge and workflows into reusable Skills.
It connects to external services via MCP
and sets automated tasks.
But more than these features,
I want you to remember two things.
First, there are so many things
we can now hand over to Agents.
And second, we've moved from the phase of asking AI questions
to the phase of managing AI.
Because in the past, when we used ChatGPT,
we'd have a question,
ask it, get an answer,
and that was it.
Now with agents like Codex, we must act as leaders:
preparing its context and environment,
and setting its task objectives.
then check its plan,
supervise its process, and approve its results.
The leader is also responsible for
turning good methods and workflows into reusable skills
and automating repetitive tasks.
Alright! Congrats on all your promotions today!
Remember to like, favorite, and follow—see you next time!